University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1890-1915
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1890-1915
AZ 406
This collection includes correspondence, financial records, and related materials concerning the establishment of the Station and its branches, its staff, equipment, operation, publications, early experiments particularly with canaigre, sugar beets, and date palms, and investigations in plant breeding, grazing lands, water and soil analysis.
University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station
11 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Establishment of the University of Arizona and the Agricultural Experiment Station were interrelated. Frank A. Gulley was appointed Dean of the first School of Agriculture in 1890. Before the opening of the University in Fall 1891, Gulley selected faculty, oversaw building projects, and issued the first publications.
Organization
This collection is organized into six series:
Series I: Correspondence and Staff Records, 1890-1915
Series II: Experiments, Investigations and Stations, 1890-1915
Series III: Books and Periodicals, 1891-1915
Series IV: Requests, 1890-1914
Series V: Equipment and Supplies, 1890-1915
Series VI: Financial Records, 1913-1915
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, financial records, and related materials concerning the establishment of the Station and its branches, its staff, equipment, operation, publications, early experiments particularly with canaigre, sugar beets, and date palms, and investigations in plant breeding, grazing lands, water and soil analysis. Correspondents include various divisions of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, other experiment stations, nurseries, seed suppliers, and Arizona residents. Also includes material relating to furnishing the University of Arizona's Old Main building, the construction of other early University buildings, and the establishment of the first student military unit.
Forbes, R. H. (Robert Humphrey), 1867-1968; Gulley, Frank A., 1850-1939; Devol, William Stowe, 1860-; Toumey, James W. (James William), 1865-1932; Comstock, Theo. B. (Theodore Bryant), 1849-1915; Boggs, Edward Marshall, 1861-; Poston, Charles D. (Charles Debrille), 1825-1902; MacDougal, Daniel Trembly, 1865-1958; Heard, Dwight B. (Dwight Bancroft), 1869-1929; University of Arizona -- Records and correspondence; University of Arizona -- History; University of Arizona -- Faculty; University of Arizona -- Buildings; University of Arizona. Dept. of Military Science and Tactics -- History; University of Arizona. Agricultural Experiment Station -- Records and correspondence; University of Arizona Board of Regents; Arizona. Territorial Prison; Agriculture -- Arizona; Horticulture -- Arizona; Irrigation -- Arizona; Pumping stations; Canaigre; Date; Date palm; Sugar beet -- Arizona; Gila River Indian Reservation (Ariz.); Santa Rita Experimental Range (Ariz.); Salt River Valley (Ariz.); Correspondence; Financial records
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence and Staff Records, 1890-1915
  - Letterbooks and University of Arizona Correspondence, 1890-1897
    Letterbooks contain outgoing correspondence only. Related incoming correspondence will be found in appropriate files throughout the collection.
    - Letterbook: Frank A. Gulley, Director. February-November 14, 1891 (Box 1)
    - Letterbook: Frank A. Gulley, Director. November 16, 1891-December 1892 (Box 1)
    - Letterbook: Frank A. Gulley, Director. January 1893-May 1894 (Box 1)
    - Letterbook: William S. Devol, Director. May-August 1895 (Box 1)
    - Letterbook: V. E. Stolbrand & Edward M. Boggs, Irrigation Engineers. August 1891-January 1897 (Box 1)
      Also includes letters written by Boggs in his capacity as Commandant of Cadets while establishing the first military unit at the University of Arizona.
    - University Correspondence: Various dealers regarding furniture, etc. for Old Main. 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - University Correspondence: Grand Rapids School Furniture Company regarding furniture, etc. for Old Main and Cottages. 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - University Correspondence: Regarding the construction and furnishings of the University of Arizona Cottages. 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - University of Arizona Commencement Items. 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural and Horticultural Correspondence, 1890-1915
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Office of Experiment Stations. 1891-1904, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Weather Bureau. 1892-1902, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Requests for Information. 1892-1902 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Regarding publications. 1895-1903 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - U. S. Department of the Interior Correspondence: Census Office. 1891-1900 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence: Seed exchanges, plant diseases, crops, etc. 1890-1905, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Division of Agrostology (grasses). 1896-1900 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Division of Botany. 1891-1900 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Division of Botany, Walter T. Swingle. 1900-1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - U. S. D. A. Correspondence: Bureau of Plant Industry. 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - University of California. 1894-1900 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Day, E. W. C., St. David, Arizona. 1903 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Graham, F. N., Yuma, Arizona. 1904 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Hartwell, Robert, Somerton, Arizona. 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Hecker, R., Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. 1902-1904 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Lewandowski, A., Douglas, Arizona. 1903-1905 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Stanton, Percy, Baja California, Mexico. 1904-1905 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Williscraft, W. H., Juniper Arizona. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Nurseries and Seed Suppliers Correspondence: Germain Fruit Co., Los Angeles, California. 1895-1904 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nurseries and Seed Suppliers Correspondence: John S. Calkins, Pomona, California. 1890-1895 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Nurseries and Seed Suppliers Correspondence: Fancher Creek Nurseries, Fresno, California. 1890-1905, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Nurseries and Seed Suppliers Correspondence: Various. 1890-1905 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Experiment Station Staff, 1890-1905
    - Horticulturist, L. E. Benton. 1891-1893 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Horticulturist, L. E. Benton: Letterbook. January 1892-March 1893 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Agriculturist and Horticulturist, A. J. McClatchie. 1897-1905 (Box 4, Folder 3-8)
    - Agriculturist and Horticulturist Applications. 1904 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Agriculturist and Horticulturist, V. A. Clark. 1904-1905 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Irrigation Engineer, Edward M. Boggs. 1892-1893 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Consulting Engineer, Sherman M. Woodward. 1904-1905 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Consulting Entomologist, T. D. A. Cockerell. 1900-1905 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Animal Husbandman Applications. 1899 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Animal Husbandman, G. H. True. 1899-1902 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - Animal Husbandman, G. H. True at Reno, Nevada. 1903-1905 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Animal Husbandman Applications. 1902 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Animal Husbandman, T. F. McConnell. 1902-1904 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Animal Husbandman, Application of J. J. Edgerton. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Animal Husbandman Applications. 1904-1905 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chemist, C. B. Collingwood. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Chemist Applications. 1894-1903 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Assistant Chemist, Mark Walker, Jr. 1884-1905 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Assistant Chemist Applications. 1899 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Associate Chemist, W. W. Skinner. 1899-1904 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Associate Chemist Applications. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Associate Chemist, Application of Howard V. Frost. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Associate Chemist, H. B. Slade. 1904-1905 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Associate Chemist Applications. 1905 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Associate Chemist, Applications of E. K. Nelson. 1899-1905 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Associate Chemist, A. E. Vinson. 1905 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Office Correspondence. 1899-1904 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with and about employees. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Search for a Gardner. 1900-1903 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - General Agriculture Applications. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Various Agricultural Departments Applications. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Office and Miscellaneous Applications. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - General Applications for the University and in Tucson, Arizona. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1890-1915
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1890-1905, 1914-1915 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
      Includes correspondence about windows for the Episcopal Church in Tucson, January-March 1893, and a letter concerning streetcar service at the University of Arizona Main Gates, January 23, 1914.
    - Correspondence: Various University of Arizona Presidents. 1890-1903 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: University of Arizona Board of Regents. 1890-1903 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Various Arizona Governors. 1891-1905 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Former Staff Correspondence: Boggs, Edward M. 1898-1900 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Former Staff Correspondence: Toumey, J. W. 1899-1905 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Former Staff Correspondence: Devol, William S. 1898-1900 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Herbert. 1899-1905 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Forbes, S. A. 1899-1905 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Heard, Dwight B. 1900-1905 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: MacDougal, D. T. 1903-1905, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Poston, Charles D. 1891-1892 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      See also Box 16, Experiment Station at Phoenix, for correspondence during 1894-1895
    - Correspondence: Scott, Chaplin Winfield. 1902-1905 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Vail, A. H. 1900-1901 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Association of American Agricultural Colleges and Experiment Stations. 1890-1905 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Association of Official Agricultural Chemists. 1892-1900 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Series II: Experiments, Investigations and Stations, 1890-1915
  - Canaigre, 1891-1914
    - Correspondence including requests for information and bulletins. 1892-1905, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 1-13)
    - Correspondence: Brewster Cameron. 1892-1893 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: J. H. Carpenter. 1892-1893 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: R. J. Kerr. 1892-1900 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: O. K. Lapham & Co. 1892-1894 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Levinstein & Sons. 1891-1897 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Schofield & Co. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Baron von St. Paul. 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Tanning Extract Co. of Peoria, Illinois. 1892-1897 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Potato Planters/Diggers. 1892-1893 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Sugar Beets, 1896-1905
    - General Correspondence. 1896-1897 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - U. S. D. A. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Growers: Towns A-Z. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
    - Form Reports. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Seed Suppliers. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Plans for a factory. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, etc. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence. 1898-1905 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Arizona Growers: Charles Arney, Thatcher. 1900-1901 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Arizona Growers: Towns A-Z. 1901-1903 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
    - Arizona Growers: John Johnson, Mesa, Arizona. 1901-1903 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Dates, 1890-1915
    - General Correspondence. 1897-1905 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: U. S. D. A. and Freight Offices regarding shipments. 1890-1905 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Requests for information and plants. 1899-1905 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - Exhibit at the St. Louis Exposition. 1904 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Growers: Bernard G. Johnson, Mecca California. 1902-1905 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Growers: N. C. Nelson, Palomas, Arizona. 1902-1905 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Fumigating Tents: William H. Hoegee Co. 1900-1905 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Harry Walker. 1900-1902 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: J. E. Price. 1900-1905 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: F. H. Simmons. 1904-1905, 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1900-1905, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Pumping Plant, Fairbanks, Morse and Co. 1904-1905 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Pumping Plant, Pacific Coast Manufacturing Co. 1904 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Pumping Plant, various firms. 1904 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Tempe Date Orchard: Well Drilling, A. J. Hansen, Kyrene, Arizona. 1904-1905 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Yuma Date Orchard: E. L. Crane. 1905 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Yuma Date Orchard: Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1904-1905 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Yuma Date Orchard: C. J. Wood. 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Pumping Plant and Swine Plague, 1891-1897
    - General Correspondence regarding a proposed pumping plant on the Pima Indian Reservation. 1891 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Proposed Pumping Plant Bids, various firms. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Proposed Pumping Plant Bids, Holly Manufacturing Co. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Swine Plague Correspondence: E. M. Depew. 1896-1897 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Swine Plage Reports, etc. 1896 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Water and Soils, 1890-1905
    - Correspondence regarding water and irrigation including use of solar power and the effect of mine tailings. 1890-1905 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - U. S. Geological Survey publications regarding water and irrigation. 1895-1903 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Artesian Wells, 1900 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Colorado River. 1899, 1903-1904 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Gila River Water: W. H. Benson. 1899-1900 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Prehistoric Canals of Tempe, Arizona. 1900 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Salt River Valley: Soil Survey. 1899-1902 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Salt River Valley: A. J. Chandler, Consolidated Canal Co., Mesa, Arizona. 1893-1904 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Salt River Valley: Irrigation Studies. 1902-1903 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Salt River Valley: Verde Water and Power Co. 1904-1905 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Water Analysis. 1893-1905 (Box 13, Folder 11-16)
  - Miscellaneous Topics, 1895-1915
    - Correspondence Courses in Agriculture. 1900-1901 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lectures. 1900-1905 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Farmers' Institutes. 1895-1905 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Grazing Lands." 1902-1904 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      An article for Out West by R. H. Forbes, presented in a talk at El Paso. Includes miscellaneous correspondence.
    - Legislation including Fertilizer laws, plant inspection, State appropriations, etc. 1895-1904 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Livestock. 1895-1905, 1913, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Plant Breeding: Cooperative Investigation with U. S. D. A. Bureau of Plant Industry. 1901-1902 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Railroad Passes. 1895-1905, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Range Grass: Cooperative Investigation with U. S. D. A. Division of Agrostology. 1900 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Santa Rita Forest Reserve. 1902-1905 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Experiment Station Publications, printing, distribution, etc. (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
  - Experiment Stations, 1890-1914
    - Phoenix Station: M. Moss. 1891-1895 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Phoenix Station: Charles D. Poston. 1894-1895 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Phoenix Station: Frederick and James Lunsford. 1895 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix Station: N. H. Claflin. 1895-1898 (Box 15, Folder 4-9)
    - Phoenix Station: Ben Eager. 1897-1898 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - Phoenix Station: Guy Acuff. 1904 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Phoenix Station: A. J. Shamblin. 1904-1905 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Phoenix Station: President Comstock and Staff. 1894-1896 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Phoenix Station: Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1890-1905 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Phoenix Station: Applications for Employment. 1894-1897 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix Station: Payroll. 1896-1897 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Phoenix Station: Miscellaneous Bills. 1895-1904 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Phoenix Station: Crop Reports. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Phoenix Station: Miscellaneous Items. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Mesa Station. 1894-1896 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Tempe Station. 1890-1895 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Tucson Station: Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1896-1897 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Tucson Station: Greenhouse Construction. 1893-1898, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Tucson Station: Payroll. 1896-1897 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Tucson Station: Travel Expenses. 1895-1897, 1901, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Tucson Station: Miscellaneous Bills. 1895-1898, 1904 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Tucson Station: Receipts for Sales. 1898-1901 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Tucson Station: Inventories. 1912 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Willcox Station. 1893-1896 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Willcox Station: J. A. Bright. 1893-1895 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Yuma Station: H. W. Blaisdell. 1890-1895, 1898 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Yuma Station: Territorial Prison Farm, etc. 1891-1896, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Financial Records, All Stations. (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Series III: Books and Periodicals, 1891-1915
  - Book Orders: McClurg & Co. 1891-1905 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Book Orders: Macmillan. 1895-1905 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Book Orders: Scientific Publishing Co. 1891-1900 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Book Orders: Miscellaneous. 1891-1905, 1914-1915 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals: Subscriptions, Back Files, Exchanges. 1892-1905 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Periodicals: Binding, Hicks-Judd Co. 1895-1905 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Publications Requested, Publications Received (Gifts). (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Requests, 1890-1914
  - Requests for Seeds. 1894-1905 (Box 19, Folder 1-11)
    Requests are mostly from Arizona residents in 1898. They are arranged alphabetically by town names.
  - Requests for Information on: the University of Arizona. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Requests for Information on: the Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Requests for Information on: Alfalfa. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Requests for Information on: Alkalai Soils. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Requests for Information on: Animal Husbandry. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Requests for Information on: Animal Pests. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Requests for Information on: Cactus. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Information on: Fertilizers, Bat Guano. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Information on: Forage Crops. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Requests for Information on: Fruits and Vegetables. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Requests for Information on: Grasses. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Requests for Information on: Insect Pests. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Requests for Information on: Irrigation and Water Pumping. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Requests for Information on: Land, Resources, Economic Conditions. (Box 20, Folder 14-15)
  - Requests for Information on: Laws. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Requests for Information on: Minerals and Mining. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Requests for Information on: Plant Diseases. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Requests for Information on: Poultry. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Requests for Information on: Sorghum and Sugar Cane. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Requests for Information on: Trees and Timber. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Requests for Information on: Weather and Climate. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Requests for Information on: What, Where and How to Plant. (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Requests for Information on: Worms. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Information on: Multiple Subjects. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Information on: Miscellaneous Subjects. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Requests for Publications: General. 1890-1899 (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
  - Requests for Publications: Arizona. 1900 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Requests for Publications: States, A-Z. 1900 (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
  - Requests for Publications: General. 1901-1906 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
  - Requests for Publications: U. S. Agricultural Experiment Stations, A-Z. (Box 23, Folder 1-6)
  - Requests for Publications: Australia. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Publications: Canada. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Publications: Great Britain. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Requests for Publications: Mexico. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Requests for Publications: Various Countries. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Requests for Articles. 1892-1905 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Requests for Photographs, etc. in Publications. 1893-1905 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Requests for Plant Identification. 1894-1905 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Requests for Plants and Cuttings. 1894-1905, 1914 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Requests for Soil Analysis and Soil Maps. 1884-1905 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Requests for Miscellaneous Analysis, including gas. 1893-1905 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Requests for Names and Lists of People. 1891-1905, 1914 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Series V: Equipment and Supplies, 1890-1915
  - Alcohol. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Animal Husbandry, Horticulture and Poultry Equipment. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Automobiles and Equipment. 1913-1915 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus: Eimer & Amend, New York City. 1894-1905 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus: Henry Heil Chemical Co., St. Louis, Missouri. 1890-1905 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus: Various dealers. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Construction Materials. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Dairy Equipment. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Farm Machinery and Equipment. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Farm Machinery, Thresher. 1913-1915 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Fences and Windmills. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Fertilizers: Ammoniates, Thomas H. White & Co., Baltimore, Maryland. 1899-1905 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Fertilizers: Nitrate of Soda. 1899-1905 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Fertilizers, Insecticides, Spraying Apparatus. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Furniture, etc., Library Bureau, St. Louis, Missouri. 1891-1905 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Furniture, etc., Macey, Grand Rapids, Michigan. 1902-1905 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Gas Machine. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Office Supplies, Shea Smith & Co., Chicago, Illinois. 1891-1905, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Office Supplies, various dealers. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Pumps and Well Drills. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Instruments: Bausch & Lomb Optical Co., Rochester, New York. 1893-1902, 1914-1915 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Instruments: Julien P. Friez, Baltimore, Maryland. 1897-1905, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Instruments: Queen & Co., Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. 1892-1904 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Instruments: Various dealers. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Instruments: Loaned by the U. S. D. A. and the U. S. G. S. 1894-1903, 1914-1915 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Equipment and Supplies. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Financial Records, 1913-1915
  - Financial Correspondence: McOmnie, A. M., Assistant Agriculturist, Head of the Phoenix Station and the Farmers' Institute. 1913-1915 (Box 27, Folder 1-5)
  - Financial Correspondence: State Auditor. 1913-1915 (Box 27, Folder 6-10)